You're single, Ms. Kinoshita?
木之下，你現在沒男友啊？
Uh, yeah.
啊，是的
How about me, then?
那要和我交往嗎？
I come with lots of amenities.
我算是優良物件哦
Oh, yeah?
這樣啊
That's so funny!
真有意思
WHAT?
（怎麼了？）
I WANT OUT OF HERE
（好想回家）
DON'T EVEN THINK ABOUT IT
（開什麼玩笑）
GRIN - GRIN
（笑嘻嘻）
I set this blind date up for you.
這是為你準備的聯誼吧？
Sorry, I'm not ready, after all.
抱歉，我覺得時機尚早
I wanna go home.
我想回家
THE FEMALE ABILITY TO CONVERSE THROUGH GAZE
（女生僅用眼神即可溝通）
Ms. Kinoshita,
木之下
you seem really into that game.
你現在很迷電玩吧？
What's it called?
是哪個遊戲？
I play mobile games too.
我也常玩手遊
Why don't we play together?
有空要不要一起玩？
Um, it's not a mobile game.
這個嘛…我不是玩手遊
It's a PC game called Forest of Savior.
是叫《救世者之森》的PC遊戲
Oh, right…
啊…
Fore…
救…
I think I've seen the TV commercial.
我好像有看過廣告
It's uh… yeah…
這個嘛…嗯…
-I saw the commercial! -Sorry about this.
-我有看過廣告 -感覺真抱歉
No, wait, I mean…
不是啦
I remember now!
是那個啊
Forest, yeah.
森林嘛
Savior, yeah.
救世者嘛
ORIGINAL STORY BY MASHIRO
（原作：Mashiro）
Unbelievable…
真是的
Were you even trying?
你有沒有心啦？
This was your chance to meet someone,
難得聯誼氣氛那麼好
and you couldn't put your phone down!
你卻狂滑手機
Are you even trying?
你有沒有幹勁啦？
Sorry.
抱歉
Ruri was messaging me, and I wanted to reply.
瑠璃傳訊息來，就聊到忘我了
Ruri?
瑠璃？
My friend from the online game.
嗯，是遊戲裡的朋友
She's a girl with this really cute avatar.
是角色造型超可愛的女孩子
A girl?
女孩子？
What'll you do if she's really an old man?
如果本人是個怪叔叔怎麼辦？
It's risky giving out your cell phone number.
隨便給手機號碼，很危險吧？
I'm pretty sure it's a girl.
我覺得…是個女孩子啊
Whatever.
那就算了
Anyway, I'm headed this way.
那我要往這邊走
Come to think of it…
這麼說起來
I never gave it any thought.
我從來沒想過耶
MY DINNER'S DONE. I'LL LOGIN AT HOME!
（聚會剛結束，我回去就登入）
RURI WILL BE HOME SOON TOO. LET'S HAVE FUN TOGETHER WHEN YOU LOGIN.
（瑠璃也快到家了 上線後一起玩吧）
In my imagination, she's a girl around high school age.
我猜瑠璃應該是個女高中生
I wonder what she's really like.
不曉得會是什麼樣的人
Wow, is that gothic Lolita fashion?
哇哦，是歌德蘿莉？
Or is it more like the cute fairytale type?
不對，是甜美夢幻系？
CAN'T TELL THESE DAYS
（搞不太懂）
Somehow…
她看起來…
She reminded me of Princess Ruri.
好有瑠璃姬的氛圍
All right…
好啦
I only have afternoon classes tomorrow,
明天下午才有課
so I can really enjoy the game tonight.
今晚可以悠閒玩遊戲了
WONDERS WHY SHE'S MORE EXCITED FOR THIS THAN HER BLIND DATE
（對於比起參加聯誼 現在更興奮的自己感到疑惑）
Well, it's no big deal.
就別想了吧
GAVE UP THINKING ABOUT IT
（決定放棄思考）
I'm just not in the mood for another romance yet.
反正我現在還沒有心情談戀愛
SYSTEM: AKANE HAS LOGGED IN
（Akane上線了）
Huh?
奇怪？
There's no one in the guild room.
公會房間裡沒人
Oh, it's Princess Ruri and Yamada!
是瑠璃姬和山田
What are they up to?
他們在做什麼啊？
Maybe the three of us can go hunting.
好想三人一起去狩獵
Let's see…
我看看…
RURI: THERE ARE NO GUILD MEMBERS ONLINE TODAY.
（今天都沒看到公會成員上線）
HERE'S ONE.
（在線上）
RURI: KINDA LONELY. AKANE'S NOT HERE EITHER…
（好寂寞哦，Akene也不在）
YAMADA: WELL, IT IS A WEEKDAY.
（畢竟是平日嘛）
RURI: SHE SAID SHE WOULD COME THOUGH.
（她剛才明明說會來）
Huh?
奇怪？
I guess they haven't noticed I'm here?
他們是不是沒發現我上線了？
THIS REMINDS ME OF WHEN THE GUILD STARTED
（感覺好像剛創公會的時候哦）
This reminds me of when the guild started.
感覺好像剛創公會的時候哦
Yeah.
是啊
It was just the two of us every day, back then.
那時每天都是我們兩人一起玩
We have a lot of members now,
現在公會已經有好多成員
but sometimes…
不過
it's nice being just the two of us.
偶爾只有我們也不錯
On one hand, there are more people to share with
現在公會越熱鬧
and on the other, I have less time alone with you.
與山田就越少機會單獨相處
Ruri's been missing that.
瑠璃覺得有點寂寞
Well,
也是
a lot of things were easier
只有兩人的時候
when it was the two of us.
反而玩起來比較順手
Th…
這…
These two are…
這兩個人…
-An item! -It's ready.
-有一腿！ -完成了
FINDING IT HARD TO INTERRUPT
（不知為何無法融入的氣氛）
Wow, thanks!
謝謝
Alchemy is such a cool skill to have!
鍊金術真是方便
Maybe Ruri should learn it too.
瑠璃我也練一下好了
By the way,
話說回來
we're not the only guild members here.
現在還有其他公會成員在啊
Oh, it's Akane!
是Akane
I missed the system log entry.
我沒注意到系統通知
Sorry, Akane!
Akane，抱歉哦
AKANE: THANKS… BUT AM I BUTTING IN?
（你們好，我會不會很礙事？）
Not at all!
才沒那回事啦
GRIN - GRIN
（笑嘻嘻）
Anyway, I have other plans, so gotta log out.
那麼我還有事，先下了
Okay!
好哦
I'll phone you later.
我晚點打電話給你
-Phone? -Right.
-打電話？ -好
SYSTEM: YAMADA HAS LOGGED OUT
（山田下線了）
Now that you mention it…
這麼說起來
Yamada barely interacts with everyone else,
山田平常很少跟其他人聊天
but he does talk to Princess Ruri a lot.
卻常常和瑠璃姬說話
Could it be they're…
他們兩人該不會…
boyfriend and girlfriend?
是男女朋友的關係？
Like when Takuma and I started playing the game together.
就像我開始和拓馬玩遊戲一樣
Maybe Yamada and Princess Ruri…
山田和瑠璃姬也是…
Akane?
Akane？
Is something wrong?
你沒精神嗎？
Not at all!
沒那回事啦
Why am I…
為什麼我…
feeling down all of a sudden?
會覺得有點沮喪呢？
THANKS FOR YOUR HELP!
（辛苦啦）
TALK TO YOU LATER!
（之後見哦）
YOU'RE THE BEST!
（愛你）
YEAH, LATER
（好，之後見）
Why am I so hung up on those two?
為什麼我會這麼在意他們？
As this example shows, social media
（山田，職業玩家）
Yamada's account…
山田的帳號…
I'd like to take a peek.
我很想看看
But then…
可是…
it sort of feels like I'd be prying.
這樣好像在探人隱私
Ms. Kinoshita!
木之下
Over here!
喂
It's the guy from that blind date.
是之前聯誼時認識的人
What was his name, again?
他叫什麼名字來著？
You had the same lecture as me, huh?
你也有上同一堂課啊
-I saw you playing with your phone. -No way!
-我在後面看到你在滑手機 -不會吧？
I didn't notice.
我都沒發現
His name… what's his name…
他的名字…名字…
It's no good. I can't remember.
不行，想不起來
By the way,
說起來
I looked up Forest of Savior after our dinner.
那天回去後，我查了你說的遊戲
It's pretty popular, huh?
那似乎蠻紅的耶
So I've heard.
的確很紅的樣子
I had the urge to try it too.
查了之後，我也開始想玩了
I like video games, after all.
畢竟我也愛玩遊戲嘛
There sure are a lot of gamer guys.
好多男生都愛電玩耶
YAMADA, PRO GAMER
（山田，職業玩家）
Do you play FPS too?
那你也有在玩FPS嗎？
"F?"
F什麼？
Do you know a pro gamer named Yamada?
你知道叫山田的職業玩家嗎？
Uh, Yamada… yeah.
嗯，山田啊
I, uh…
這個嘛…
-I may have seen him in a commercial! -Sorry again.
-我好像有看過廣告 -真的很抱歉
You really are into games, aren't you?
你真的很迷電玩耶
What is this…?
怎麼回事？
I have this vaguely uneasy feeling.
總覺得心情一直好焦躁
And so, when summer arrives,
然後啊，就聊到夏天時
our circle is talking about going to Okinawa.
要和社團的人一起去沖繩玩
It will be!
很好玩哦
Our members all know how to have a good time.
大家都很會炒熱氣氛
-Why don't you join us? -Huh?
-你要不要也一起去？ -奇怪？
That girl…
我記得那個女生…
Haven't I seen her before?
我之前好像有看過…
Sorry I'm late.
久等了
Let's go.
走吧
The hotel we book regularly has an ocean view!
我們常訂的旅館有海景…
I've never had a girlfriend.
我也沒交過女友
Well…
畢竟…
Yamada is handsome.
山田長得很帥
I was sure he must have had
我之前就覺得
a girlfriend or two, at least.
他交過一兩個女友也不奇怪
Ms. Kinoshita?
木之下？
Sorry, I'm headed this way.
我要往這個方向，失陪了
-Ms. Kinoshita-- -See you on campus!
-木之下… -之後學校見了
So why…?
可是…
Why do I feel so uneasy?
為什麼我會這麼焦躁？
I think I'll skip logging in today.
今天還是別上線好了
Who's that?
是誰啊？
Momo, maybe?
小桃嗎？
HI THERE, AKANE! ARE YOU FREE?
（Akane，哈囉， 現在有空嗎？）
It's Princess Ruri.
是瑠璃姬
What do I do?
怎麼辦？
I'm not in the mood for gaming today.
我今天沒什麼心情玩遊戲
HI THERE RURI, WHAT'S UP?
（瑠璃，哈囉！怎麼了？）
AKANE, DID YOU READ THE FOS NEWS?
（Akane 你有看《FOS新聞》嗎？）
FOS News?
《FOS新聞》？
I haven't logged in today, so I don't know about it.
我今天沒上線，沒看到哦…傳送
THEY'RE OPENING A FOS COLLABORATIVE CAFE NEXT MONTH. WANNA GO TOGETHER?
（下個月要開聯名咖啡廳哦 要不要一起去？）
A collaborative cafe?
聯名咖啡廳啊
OH, AND I RAN INTO YAMADA IRL AND INVITED HIM TOO! AND THE OTHER MEMBERS!
（對了，我在線下巧遇山田 剛才也約了他）
"Ran into him IRL…"
在線下巧遇…
Could it be…
難不成…
That girl really is Princess Ruri?
那個女生真的是瑠璃姬？
I did get the same kind of vibe from her.
她的確很有瑠璃姬的氛圍
But then, those two really are…
這麼說來，那兩人果然…
RURI WOULD LOVE TO MEET OFFLINE! CAN YOU COME?
（好想和Akane在線下見面 你願意嗎？）
P-L-E-A-S-E!
（求求你了）
OKAY, I'LL GO
（好啊，一起去吧）
GOOD MORNING, AKANE
（Akane早安啊，就是今天了）
TODAY'S THE DAY!
（瑠璃期待到昨晚都沒睡好）
I'M SO EXCITED I COULD BARELY SLEEP!
（好想趕快見到Akane哦）
Well, I guess I'll get ready.
好啦，來準備吧
I won't get many opportunities to meet the guild members IRL.
難得和遊戲公會成員實際見面
I should enjoy it.
這個機會很少見嘛
MEETING OFFLINE?
（線下聚會？）
IS THAT SAFE? YOU'VE NEVER SEEN THEM BEFORE, RIGHT?
（沒問題嗎？都是沒見過的人吧）
IT'S FINE! THEY'RE ALL NICE
（別擔心！大家人都很好）
AND YAMADA WILL BE THERE TOO!
（而且山田也在）
YAMADA WILL BE THERE? THAT'S A RELIEF
（山田也會去啊？我安心多了）
HAVE FUN!
（玩得開心哦）
Yeah, let's have fun!
樂在其中吧
Now then…
我看看…
The Murata building outside the north exit…
車站北區有棟村田大樓…
MURATA BUILDING
（村田大樓）
…will be on your left when you cross the street.
確認在左邊後，直走過馬路
And then…?
接下來是…
Better check the map again.
再看一次地圖
SOBA RESTAURANT
（蕎麥麵）
Where is it?
在哪啊？
FREEZE
（停下）
IN A HURRY…
啊
-Oh, excuse me! -Not at all!
-對不起 -沒事
-It was my fault-- -Let me get that for you.
-我幫你撿 -是我停下來看地圖…
I hope your phone isn't broken.
希望螢幕沒裂開
SORRY…
（不好意思…）
You're going to the FOS cafe?
你要去FOS的聯名咖啡廳？
By any chance…
難不成…
do you play the game?
你有在玩那個遊戲？
It's a fairly casual game,
因為算是蠻輕鬆的遊戲
so I heard there were a lot of girls playing,
聽說女性玩家比例很高
but I didn't know there were any
但沒想到有這麼漂亮的玩家
as pretty as you.
真是嚇我一跳
Come on, I'm not that…
沒有啦，你過獎了
I followed him because he said he'd lead me there,
他說要帶路，我就跟著走了
but what if this is a new kind of scam?
但如果是新的攬客手法怎麼辦？
HE KEEPS COMPLIMENTING ME TOO…
（他一直誇我又超親切）
I started playing with a friend,
我剛開始是和朋友一起玩
but I've gotten really into it.
現在玩得很迷
We even started a guild together.
還一起創了公會
I thought it would be your average MMO,
本以為是常見的多人線上遊戲
but it actually has a solid balance of elements.
沒想到遊戲平衡調整得很好
My favorite feature is how they prevent
最讓我滿意的就是
characters from over-buffing through purchases.
不會因為花越多錢就越強
It's true that the GFX are a bit out of date,
雖然遊戲畫面有點落伍啦
but the cuteness makes up for it.
但這樣其實也蠻可愛的
Best of all, there are no super races.
最重要的是沒有特別強大的種族
I enjoy seeing diverse characters
畢竟玩家想看看各種角色
and I bet the difference in classes isn't that big either.
在職業上也沒有一職獨大的現象
Mages do have a slight advantage now,
雖然現在魔職偏多
but each update leads closer to perfect balance.
每次更新都有恰到好處的調整
And thanks to guild enhancements,
多虧有公會的強化效果
there's a reason to fight.
讓公會戰的好處更加明顯
The game is built to encourage parties.
是要強調組隊的樂趣吧
It gives meaning to playing together.
這樣才更有交流的意義
Of course, leveling up can be nerve wracking,
雖然同時增加了強化的難度
but it works well for self-imposed challenges.
但也多了挑戰極限的樂趣
I really feel like the developer is listening to users.
看來營運這次有認真聽玩家心聲
I can tell they've learned from their previous mistakes.
能明白他們以上次的失敗作為教訓
Phew. He's just your average gamer.
太好了，只是個電玩迷
Anyway, that's my take. What's yours?
我個人是這麼想啦
-What do you think? -Huh?
-你覺得如何？ -什麼？
Um…
這個嘛…
I'm still new to all of this
我還只是個新手
and I don't know as much as everyone else.
不像大家一樣懂那麼多
I even got in trouble
像前陣子
for putting "garbage" in the guild treasure chest.
還有人罵我別在公會倉庫塞垃圾
But then, the Guild Master is really kind
不過，公會的會長很親切
and I like the group I'm with…
我還蠻喜歡現在的公會…
Oh, I think I see him.
好像來了
Hey! Over here!
喂，在這邊哦
This way!
這邊
It's over here!
這邊哦
Isn't that…
那個女生…
Princess Ruri?
是瑠璃姬？
I didn't know you played that game.
原來山田有玩那個遊戲啊
-Let's battle, sometime. -Sure.
-下次我們來對戰吧 -好啊
Yamada!
山田
Yamada! It's been a while.
山田，好久不見
Long time no see.
好久不見
-How've you been? -Same as usual.
-你過得好嗎？ -蠻普通的
Same as usual, huh?
很普通啊
STARE
（直盯）
Oh, you're Princess Ruri, aren't you?
你是瑠璃姬吧？
Nice to meet you.
幸會
HOW CUTE
（好可愛）
You look just like your character.
你和角色的印象一樣
I recognized you right away.
我馬上就認出你了
Thank you for your message this morning!
謝謝你早上傳訊息給我
Huh?
怪了？
Her personality seems a bit different from in the game.
感覺和遊戲裡的氛圍不太一樣
Um…
那個…
Hey, Eita.
欸，瑛太
Who is this girl?
這個人是誰？
If I'm correct…
我猜她…
you're Akane,
就是Akane
aren't you?
沒錯吧？
Excuse me…
那個…
Everyone, why don't we at least go inside?
大家要不要先進去再說…
IZAKAYA BOTTA
（博大居酒屋）
Home at last…
終於到了
My back hurts…
好痛…
How is she so damn heavy?
有夠重的
*UNCONSCIOUS PEOPLE ARE ALL HEAVY
（失去意識的人特別重）
I'm beat…
累死了
IT'S PRACTICE TIME, BUT YOU'RE OFFLINE?
（我已經開始練習了 山田離線了？）
Uh-oh…
糟糕
*YAMADA BELONGS TO A PRO FPS TEAM
（山田有加入 FPS遊戲的職業隊伍）
You're late! Where've you been?
慢死了，你在搞什麼啊？
You've kept us all waiting.
大家都在等你哦
Please excuse me. Actually…
抱歉，其實…
through a turn of events…
算是順其自然…
a woman I don't know is asleep in my room.
現在有個陌生女人睡在我房裡
TANI-YAN
（牛蒡）
KIM, GOBOU,
（漆黑的Aqua）
A woma…
（金）
JET BLACK AQUA,
（阿谷）
A woman?!
女人？
"A woman?"
你剛才說了“女人”？
-Unforgivable… -He did, right?
-你說了“女人”？ -不饒你…
-Show this wayward soul the error of… -He said "woman"!
-說了“女人”沒錯吧？ -罪孽深重的異教徒
Is someone reading an incantation?
是不是有人一直在唸咒？
Hey, photos…
欸，照片
I wanna see a photo!
我想看照片
I won't spread it anywhere!
我絕不會外流的
I have rather high digital literacy!
我的網路素養很好的
Not a chance.
不行
Trust your team members!
你要相信隊友啦
I feel sick…
好不舒服…
Hold to him the mirror
交出畫面吧
that he may see how he has sinned.
這樣即可免除汝的罪行…
I have to step away.
我離開一下
Hey, Yamada! Wait!
喂，山田，等等
Now I'm pissed off. I'm gonna slander your account.
我不爽了，我要去鬧你的帳號
-Please don't. -So much for digital literacy.
-不可以 -有夠沒素養
Excuse me…
那個…
Are you okay?
你沒事吧？
Do you need water or anything?
要喝水嗎？
Nothing.
我不需要
After all…
反正…
you don't…
你已經…
love me anymore, do you?
不喜歡我了吧？
Then go…
既然這樣…
Hurry up and leave me.
就給我走遠一點
Go!
快走啦
She says that
嘴巴上這麼說
while clinging to me…
手卻緊抓著不放
Isn't that a contradiction?
太矛盾了吧？
Or so I thought,
但是想歸想
but this seems different, somehow.
應該有哪裡不一樣吧？
I don't get it.
我不懂
WOMEN'S HEARTS ARE THE HARDEST GAME OF ALL
（女人心真難懂）
Even so…
不過
If I move from here…
要是我現在離開
I get the feeling… she'll cry even harder.
這個人…應該會哭得更兇
SHE FINALLY FELL ASLEEP…
（終於睡了…）
She's been crying, non-stop…
這個人從頭哭到尾
She must really be hurt.
到底是多難過啊？
I guess…
總覺得…
love is pretty hard on people.
談戀愛還真是辛苦
Just sleep quietly until morning.
拜託你乖乖睡到早上吧
I'm gonna barf!
我要吐了